Michael Da Silva

devMichaelDaSilva@gmail.com ProgrammedMikey.github.io Tel. 407-300-4392

Extensive international experience, extremely creative and highly efficient in web details, deep experience in web application development and management. Profound understanding of computer languages, as well as the principles and techniques of building and maintaining different sites and servers.

✓ Objective: Web Developer

Academic training

Florida Technical College – Orlando, FL USA. Bachelor of Computer Science 2016 graduate.

Courses

System development SENAI (Brazil) 2018

Languages

Fluent in english and portuguese (Write/Read/Oral)

Professional Experience:

Vijilan Security - Orlando, Florida

05/2020 - 02/2021

Product Developer (9 Months Contract)

- Integrated multiple third party software's with Lumen into the main partner portal.
- Created multiple custom features in the porter portal created with PHP and JavaScript inside Drupal CMS.
- Coded components in an Agile and SCRUM environment from home utilizing a test driven development approuch.

IntegrateSoftware – Belo Horizonte, Brazil

09/2018 - 12/2019.

Mobile Developer

- Rebuilt the iOS and Android app that was originally built with Joomla for the Web.
- Designed and developed application to create, view and edit invoices and manage your account, a invoice system.
- Developed the IOS and Android front end application with ionic 4 and Angular, including the larvel REST API
- Design and development or backend REST API with Laravel and MySQL.

BuilderAll - Orlando, Florida USA

01/2017 - 06/2018.

Software Developer

- Designed and developed Email Marketing software.
- Collaborated with Designers to create clean interfaces with intuitive interactions and simple experiences.
- Performed detailed programming and developed websites for internal and external audiences, with backend server code.
- Reinforced all dynamic and interactive Email Marketing software for a better user experience and user interface, resulting in a 40% increase in sales revenue.

MYGSPN — Clermont, Florida USA

Software Developer

02/2016 - 12/2016.

- Developer Analyst using social media application for high school sports.
- Systems Reengineering using various methodologies. (Language / PowerBuilder / Java, Sybase / Oracle)
- Developed applications using JavaScript / Angular for the front end, contributing to all professional areas
- Implementation and migration of systems to Java platform, as well as maintenance of PHP backend development for dynamic database based applications.
 Management and Consulting in various projects of the company.

Villa Marketers — St. Cloud, Florida USA

05/2015 - 01/2016

Web Developer

- Website design according to Accessibility, Web Interface Usability, XHTML, HTML and CSS code validation.
- Management on various web platforms using HTML / CSS, bootstrap, Java script, jQuery, PHP and MySQL
- Preparation of functional specifications, mapping and monitoring software installation.
- Projec t Coordination of Web Application Development, PHP programming, ASP, Tableless HTML
 design, JavaScripts, Database Management (MySql, Microsoft SQL Server), systemic view on network
 and server administration, and deployment of security and encryption features in web applications
- Ensured site usability through implementation and Search Engine Optimization to improve results and business flow.

Additional Skills

- Nginx / Apache
- Web Security
- Web Sockets
- QA, Unit Testing
- NoSQL & MySQL
- Eloquent/Mongoose
- FTP, SSH & CPanel
- WordPress, CMS
- Terminal Usage

- Server Deployment
- Agile practitioner
- HTML, CSS, PHP & JavaScript
- frameworks
- Laravel, Angular & React
- Function & OOP design
- Rest API & MVC design
- Scaling and Optimizing